Sel Norman

971-344-7403 | Hillsboro, Oregon selnorman.developer@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full stack developer skilled in mobile-first responsive design and test-driven development. Experienced with modern tooling and coding methodologies.

SKILLS

Proficient in creating interactive web apps and APIs using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES5, ES6 and JSX), JSON Web Tokens, React.js, React Native, React Router, and Redux on the front-end,

with **Node.js**, **Passport.js**, **MongoDB** and **PostgreSQL**, **KNEX.js** backends. Continuous Integration and testing experience using **Mocha**, **Chai**, **Git/GitHub**, **Travis CI** and **Heroku**.

DevOps server and network infrastructure design and installation. Banking application design, development, data conversion, production support.

PROJECTS

Full Stack Developer | Blooms Subscription Service https://blooms-pdx.herokuapp.com/ React, React Router, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo

A responsive web app that lets you send flowers to to a recipient at a residence or business according to a schedule.

Full Stack Developer | Cozy Spaces https://cozy-spaces-client.herokuapp.com/

React, React Router, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo, Google Map API

Cozy Spaces is focused on bringing a warm glow to life through curating truly cozy spaces, especially for anyone experiencing cold climates, and/or nostalgia of a cozier time.

is an app that allows people to find and recommend cozy spots to hang out in their vicinity

Full Stack Developer | Emoji Madness https://emoji-space-rep-client.herokuapp.com/

React, Redux, Node, Express, Mongo

This app will help you to learn the emoji language symbols that easily bridge language barriers, save time, and add emotional nuance easier than with text. Spaced repetition learning helps users retain knowledge easier by testing them more often on the things they forget most frequently.

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful / Full Stack Developer Apprentice

June 2018 - November 2018 Portland, OR

Completed intensive 50+ hour per week online program. Created and deployed mobile-first applications using best industry practices and software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node, React, React Native, Redux, and algorithms & data structures. Learned new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every day with a senior developer and a team of engineers.

Snoring Cat LLC / Managing Partner

May 2017 - Present Portland, OR

Co-owner of a flower and houseplant shop in Downtown Portland. Developing custom software to provide new floral industry

services.

Riot Games / Data Center Engineer

Aug 2011 - March, 2016 Santa Monica, CA

Designed, assembled and managed data center network and server infrastructure across the USA, Japan and Australia to support Riot's growth from 1.4 million daily players in August 2011 to more than 100 million daily players in 2016.

J.Racenstein Company / Technology Manager

June 2007 - June 2009, Carson, CA

Purchased, configured and maintained multi-company servers, Exchange, SQL, VoIP servers, operating systems, network, VPNs, workstations and office equipment.

Developed marketing quiz websites with prize giveaways.

Hogan IDS / Software Consultant

1991 - 2001, International

Bank merger and acquisition data conversion mapping, scrubbing, SQL queries, sampling and testing for Customer Information System and Integrated Deposits System.

Developed Overdraft Processing, REA statements, ACH transactions, Employee Stock Purchase Plan transaction processing, Regulatory and Financial reporting.

Production support, troubleshooting and problem resolution for Hogan Deposits and CIS systems that processed 30+ million customer records.

IBM New Orleans, LA Wells Fargo Bank Minneapolis, MN First Chicago Bank Chicago, IL U.S. Bank St. Paul, MN Norwest Bank St. Paul, MN First Bank Minneapolis, MN Banco Internacional Toluca, Mexico Tempe, AZ First Interstate Bank Hogan Systems Dallas, TX **Dominion Bank** Roanoke, VA Key Bank Albany, NY Hibernia Bank New Orleans, LA V.U.B. Bratislava, Slovakia Comerica Bank Auburn Hills, MI

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Engineering Visual Basic, ASP, MSSQL, Oracle College <u>Thinkful</u> <u>Compu</u>

Economics Major <u>Carleton College</u>